ADENIYI MICHEAL ADERINTO

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A Technical Product Owner with Business Analysis, product management, systems Integration, Cloud technology, Mobile Communications, Telecommunications, and Digital experience. As a team player within dedicated IT delivery teams, I have owned and driven meaningful initiatives through various software delivery life cycles in order to deliver value. Combining strong analytic and technical skills I have bridged gaps between business and IT teams within the project environment thereby achieving and often exceeding set targets.

CONTACT

Address: Cheadle Road, Cheadle Hulme., Stockport, Greater Manchester SK8 5ET

Phone: 07846226806

Email: micheal.aderinto@gmail.com

WORK HISTORY

Technical Product Owner 04/2022 to Date WMI-Animal Health / Amerisourcebergen - Manchester.

- Defined the roadmap of features for the MWI veterinary practice information management system (MERLIN)
- Elicited and documented requirements from customers, ensuring the resulting user stories meat the definition of ready criteria. (DOR)
- Ensured delivery in an agile methodology (SCRUM), facilitated scrum ceremonies – sprint planning, daily stand-ups, refinement sessions and retrospective sessions.
- Delivered solutions that streamlined and automated workflows, saving customers time and approximately 20% cost saving YOY, Increasing user satisfaction and improved user experience.
- Led partnership and integration initiatives with other service/solution providers, exploring business models that are mutually beneficial to ourselves, partners, and deliver real value to customers.
- Championed the working group responsible for prioritizing the resolution of bugs and defects.

Business Analyst 01/2021 to 04/2022 Barclays Bank UK - Manchester.

- Worked across multiple stakeholders within multiple areas of the bank to identify, gather and document high level requirements for Cloud Migration of Bank recoveries system, resulting in cost savings approx.. £1.4M
- Developed robust criteria for DOR (definition of ready) and DOD (Definition of done), which resulted in 37% increase in team velocity.
- Led and facilitated requirement workshops and focussed group sessions to drill down to obtain and document low level functional and non-functional requirements. Ensuring that
- Work with solution architects to evaluate and prepare solution options. (Played key role in determining recommended option)
- Document low level requirements as user stories in Jira

- Lead development team to estimate story points and efforts required to deliver requirements
- Facilitated scrum ceremonies sprint planning, daily stand-ups, refinement sessions and retrospective sessions.

Business Analyst /Product Owner, 12/2018 to 01/2021 Thebigword - Leeds

- Reduced organisational operating costs by 10% by streamlining linguist registration processes.
- Worked well with both external and internal clients to define business and system requirements to build language interpreting and translation software solutions.
- Delivery of completed and quantifiable business benefits.
- Worked to deadlines and managed client/internal customer's expectations on project delivery.
- Worked with and managed outsourced development activities.
- Managed project build, highlighting issues/key dependencies/further requirements.
- Responsible for all scrum ceremonies
- Managed multiple on-going software projects.
- Chaired requirement elicitation workshops to gather and document business requirements.
- Assisted business users, project managers and executives when necessary.
- Created, review and update user manuals and procedures.
- Led cross-functional teams to analyse and understand operational impacts and opportunities of technology changes.
- Collaborated on all stages of systems development life cycle, from requirements gathering to production releases.

Snr BA, 01/2018 to 12/2018 Lake Liberty Ltd - Veyrier, Geneva

- Successfully captured and defined user requirements for this digital transformation project which Including website revamp, cloud migration and CRM System consolidation for two merging companies. This project was delivered on time and within 80% of approved budget.
- Lead scrum meetings including Sprint Planning, stand-ups, retrospectives, and demos
- Built and maintained relationships with key business stakeholders across multiple global locations and ensured all stakeholders were kept updated and informed.
- Carried out data analysis by identifying sources, gap analysis, requirements for migration and integration to end systems.
- Collaborated with design and development teams to ensure that completed technical artefacts satisfy the documented business and usability requirements.
- Supported the discovery phase of a CRM System enhancement solution (Carried out feasibility studies and options analysis) (Salesforce vs Open source).
- Authored strategic roadmap to show reduced costs, third party reliance and improved customer experience

 Resolved risks and issues, providing timely updates to the program, project and BA teams.

Business Analyst / PM, 07/2017 to 12/2017 Sterling Careers Ltd - London, London

- Led Digital Transformation of IT training centre to e-learning platform, implemented Salesforce, acted as liaison between business team and development team throughout the project life cycle and delivered the project on time.
- Facilitated workshops to identify and capture high-level business requirements.
- Analysed existing process and defined to-be processes of new elearning platform which led to a 50% increase in signups. Thereby significantly increasing revenue.
- Lead scrum meetings including Sprint Planning, stand-ups, retrospectives, and demos
- Engaged user groups to undertake Learning Needs •
- Worked with product owner to elicit and document detailed requirements for the LMS (Learning management system) and CRM using User stories based on gherkin syntax.
- Performed options analysis of market leading LMS and CRM solutions and made recommendations to business.
- Had responsibility for analysing and producing customer personas & customer journey maps from user research reports •Conducted analysis of various competitors' websites.
- Worked within 'Agile' delivery team, in planning and scheduling development backlog into sprints, hence effectively managed change, ensuring robust assessment and impact analysis of proposed change on the L&D unit.
- Developed metrics used to determine inefficiencies and areas for improvement.
- Collaborated with training unit team members to design new applications system to enhance client requirements for mobile computing capabilities.
- Analysed key aspects of business to evaluate factors driving results and summarised into presentations.
- Identified workflow bottlenecks and implemented new and improved processes and policies.

Business Analyst/Consultant, 04/2012 to 07/2017 YemdelMobile Partners LTD - Lagos

- Integration of MTN Nigeria's mobile subscribers' database with NCC's centralised database as part of regulatory requirements.
- Supported requirements gathering workshops, engaging relevant stakeholders, in order to understand regulatory requirement, analysed, validated, documented and prioritised business/ system requirements. This project was delivered 3 months ahead of schedule.
- Produced detailed requirements specifications, to provide clarity to business and technical stakeholders.
- Set up project governance framework including data governance framework •Work with business project managers to produce user guides in support of new system development, as well as workflows for ongoing management and support

- Produced wireframes and customer journey maps to support detailed solution design •Documented integration scenarios, liaison with key stakeholders to ensure all requirements were adequately captured and signed-off.
- Utilised data analysis in assessing processes and procedural issues, making recommendations to ensure compliance with business rules.
- Worked within agile, hybrid and waterfall methodology.
- Supported testing phase (documenting business scenarios for UAT).

EDUCATION

Business Analysis Foundation (BCS)
AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
B.ENG, Electrical Engineering, 1996
OneTrust Certified Privacy Management Professional
ICAgile Certified Product Owner